Finding Aid for the Renée Levine Packer Papers, 1963-circa 2015
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Photographs, circa 1964-1992, IX.; Item 474-539
  - Renée Levine and Morton Feldman, 1977, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 479)
    Haupt, Irene
  - Renée Levine and John Cage, 1982-03, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 480)
    Freeman, Betty
  - Renée Levine and John Cage, 1982-03, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 481)
  - Renée Levine and John Cage, 1982-03, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 482)
  - Renée Levine and John Cage, 1982-03, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 483)
  - Renée Levine and John Cage, 1982-03, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 484)
  - Renée Levine portrait, 1983, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 485)
  - Renée Levine and John Cage, 1982-03, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 486)
  - Renée Levine portrait, 1983, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 487)
  - Renée Levine standing in a doorway, 1984, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 488)
  - Renée Levine standing in a doorway, 1984, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 489)
  - Renée Levine and Virgil Thomson, 1984, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 490)
  - Renée Levine and Virgil Thomson, 1984, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 491)
  - Renée Levine and Virgil Thomson, 1984, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 492)
  - Renée Levine and Virgil Thomson, 1984, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 493)
  - Renée Levine and Betsy Jolas at Cal Arts, circa 1983, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 494)
    Brown, Earle
  - Renée Levine and Betsy Jolas at Cal Arts, circa 1983, 1 color photograph (Box 22, Item 495)
  - Renée Levine and Betsy Jolas at Cal Arts, circa 1983, 1 color photograph (Box 22, Item 496)
  - Renée Levine and Betsy Jolas at Cal Arts, circa 1983, 1 color photograph (Box 22, Item 497)
  - Renée Levine and Betsy Jolas at Cal Arts, circa 1983, 1 color photograph (Box 22, Item 498)
  - Renée Levine, Steve Reich, and John Cage, circa 1983?, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 499)
  - Renée Levine, Steve Reich, and John Cage, circa 1983?, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 500)
  - Renée Levine and James Turrell, between 1980 and 1989, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 501)
  - Renée Levine, Kyle Gann, John Cage, and Jan Williams at New Music America, Miami, 1988, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 502)
    Niblock, Phill
  - Renée Levine and Steve Reich, 1992-10-09, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 503)
  - Renée Levine, Steve Reich, and Beryl Korot, 1992-10-09, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 504)
  - Renée Levine and unidentified man, 1970, 1 color photograph (Box 22, Item 505)
  - Renée Levine at desk in Baird Hall, 1966-12-15, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 506)
  - Renée Levine, Buell Neidlinger, and John Bergamo, circa 1965, 1 color photograph (Box 22, Item 507)
  - Marijke Verberne at Niagara Falls, 1970, 1 color photograph (Box 22, Item 508)
  - Renée Levine and Eberhard Blum in London, 1974, 1 color photograph (Box 22, Item 509)
    Williams, Jan
  - Renée Levine sitting in Albright-Knox Art Gallery auditorium, circa 1967, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 510)
  - John Tilbury at Niagara Falls, circa 1969, 1 color photograph (Box 22, Item 511)
  - Gwendolyn Sims Warren, 1969, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 512)
  - Renée Levine, Jan Williams, Lukas Foss and George Ritscher At Rutgers University, 1970, 1 color photograph (Box 22, Item 513)
  - Gwendolyn Sims Warren and Jacques Guyonnet at Rutgers University, 1970, 1 color photograph (Box 22, Item 514)
  - University at Buffalo campus during student unrest, 1970, 1 color photograph (Box 22, Item 515)
  - Renée Levine, Woody Vasulka, Steina Vasulka, Amy and Jack Bice in Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1980, 1 color photograph (Box 22, Item 516)
  - Richard Dufallo conducting Creative Associates Shaul Ben-Meir, Cornelius Cardew, Robert Martin, Klaus von Wrochem, Jan Williams, Andrew White, and Makoto Michi in rehearsal of work by Stefan Wolpe at Albright-Knox Art Gallery, 1966, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 517)
  - Charles Haupt, Robert Martin, Jean Dupouy, Carlos Roque Alsina, Anne Graff, William Penn, Warren Hoffer, Andrew White, Klaus von Wrochem, Ed Burnham, Robert Beckworth, Jan Williams, and Makoto Michi, 1966-03-19, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 518)
  - Renée Levine, David Rosenboom, Miriam Abramowitsch, Carlos Roque Alsina, Charles Haupt, Jonathan Marcus, Harley Gaber, Jerry Kirkbride, Merete Bekkelund, Jon Hassell, Robert Martin, and Stuart Dempster,1967, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 519)
    Gena, Peter
  - Photomontage titled Who are these people? Creative Associates, 1968?, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 520)
  - Proof sheet of photographs of rehearsal of L'histoire du soldat with Ned Regan, Seymour Knox, Lukas Foss, and Max Clarkson, 1973-10, 1 proof sheet (Box 22, Item 521)
  - Proof sheet of photographs of rehearsal of L'histoire du soldat with Ned Regan, Seymour Knox, Lukas Foss, and Max Clarkson, 1973-10, 1 proof sheet (Box 22, Item 522)
  - Proof sheet of photographs of Creative Associates, including Renée Levine, Eberhard Blum, Dennis Kahle, Ben Hudson, and others, 1973-09-23, 1 proof sheet (Box 22, Item 523)
  - Proof sheet of photographs of Creative Associates, including Dennis Kahle, Julius Eastman, Eberhard Blum, and Stuart Fox, 1973-11-13, 1 proof sheet (Box 22, Item 524)
  - Proof sheet of photographs of Creative Associates, including Eberhard Blum, 1973?, 1 proof sheet (Box 22, Item 525)
  - Proof sheet of photographs of Creative Associates, including Eberhard Blum, 1973?, 1 proof sheet (Box 22, Item 526)
  - Lukas Foss portrait, 1971, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 527)
    Freeman, Betty?
  - Lukas Foss portrait, 1971, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 528)
  - Lukas Foss with wife Cornelia and their children, at Paradise Island, 1971, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 529)
  - Jesse Levine at a rehearsal, 1965, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 530)
  - Betty Freeman and Franco Assetto, undated, 1 color photograph (Box 22, Item 531)
  - Pauline Oliveros and Gordon Mumma, undated, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 532)
  - Carol Plantamura at Cal Arts, 1982, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 533)
  - Woody and Steina Vasulka, 1976-09-16, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 534)
  - Julius Eastman (back row) with other children at summer camp, undated, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 535)
  - Julius Eastman with his family, undated, 1 black and white photograph (Box 22, Item 536)
  - John Cage portrait photograph in tiff format, undated, 1 CD-ROM (Box 22, Item 537)
  - Four images of Julius Eastman in both jpeg and tiff format, undated, 1 CD-ROM (Box 22, Item 538)
    Unidentified photographers
  - Forty-one images of Julius Eastman, undated, 1 CD-ROM (Box 22, Item 539)
    Burkhardt, Donald
- Scores, 1967-1982, X.; Item 540-548
  Dates stated represent publication or completion date, not date of inscription or acquisition.
  Alphabetically arranged by composer surname and then by title.
  - Cardew, Cornelius: Treatise, 1967, 1 score (193 pages) (Box 23, Item 540)
    Gallery Upstairs Press
  - Eastman, Julius: Colors, 1973, 1 score (17 pages) (Box 23, Item 541)
    Holograph (reproduction) with annotations, some in color. Accompanied by score of same work as retrieved by Mary Jane Leach's website.
  - Eastman, Julius: Moon's silent modulation, 1970, 1 score (20 pages) (Box 23, Item 542)
    Holograph (reproduction). Movement 1 possibly incomplete. Includes second copy of movement 3 with different markings. Also, accompanied by score of same work as retrieved by Mary Jane Leach's website.
  - Eastman, Julius: Three pieces for violin and piano. Pieces 1-2, 1969, 1 score (2 pages) (Box 23, Item 543)
    Holograph (reproduction). Incomplete.
  - Eastman, Julius: Thruway, 1970, 1 score (21 leaves) (Box 23, Item 544)
    Holograph (reproduction). Annotated ozalid copy.
  - Eastman, Julius: Untitled work, between 1970-1979, 1 score (33 leaves) (Box 23, Item 545)
    Holograph (reproduction). Annotated ozalid copy. For tape, chorus, strings, and percussion.
  - Feldman, Morton: Three voices, 1982, 1 score (18 pages) (Box 23, Item 546)
    Holograph (reproduction).
  - Silsbee, Ann: Prometheus: Dramatic cantata for solo bass voice, mixed chorus and instruments, 1972, 1 score (47 pages) (Box 23, Item 547)
    Holograph (reproduction). Annotated copy. Typescript program notes and texts included, as well as concert program for performance by Cornell Chamber Chorale and S.E.M. Ensemble 22 July 1973.
  - Sigurbjörnsson, Thorkell: For Renée: for flute, violoncello, piano and percussion, 1977, 1 score (13 pages) (Box 23, Item 548)
    Boosey and Hawkes. Includes letter and concert program for premiere performance, 19 January 1974 in Toronto.
- Sound recordings, 1968-2011, XI.; Item 549-571
  Many of the recordings bear inscriptions form composers.
  Separated by format and then alphabetically arranged by composer surname and then by title.
  - Antonio, Humberto: El charro de oro. Canciones de Ayer, de hoy y de sempre, 1989, 1 12 inch sound disc (Box 24, Item 549)
    Harmony H 1001. Inscribed by Antonio to Renée Levine-Packer.
  - India, Sigismondo d': Arie, madrigali e motetti, 1978, 1 12 inch sound disc (Box 24, Item 550)
    Italia ITL 70026. Inscribed by Carol Plantamura to Renée Levine-Packer.
  - Music: 16th and 17th century music, 1985, 1 12 inch sound disc (Box 24, Item 551)
    Leonarda LPI 123. Inscribed by Carol Plantamura to Renée Levine-Packer.
  - Pablo, Luis de: Colleccion de musica contemporanea 5, 1971, 1 12 inch sound disc (Box 24, Item 552)
    Clave: 18-5005 S. Inscribed by Luis de Pablo on insert to Renée Levine-Packer.
  - Sahl, Michael: Music from Exiles' Café, 1985, 1 12 inch sound disc (Box 24, Item 553)
    Musical Heritage Society MHS 7097F. Inscribed by Michael Sahl to Renée Levine-Packer.
  - Stone, Carl: Woo lae oak, 1983, 1 12 inch sound disc (Box 24, Item 554)
    Wizard Records 224. Inscribed by Carl Stone to Renée Levine-Packer.
  - Stravinsky, Igor: Oedipus Rex, 1968, 1 12 inch sound disc (Box 24, Item 555)
    Cornell University. Features performance by Julius Eastman singing the bass part. The disc contains sides 2-3 of 4 sides on 2 discs.
  - Conversations in the arts, 1978-03-07, 1 U-matic video cassette (Box 24, Item 556)
    Profile of Renée Levine Packer for show hosted by Esther Swartz Harriott for International Cable TV.
  - Brown, Earle: Music for chamber orchestra, 1997, 1 compact disc (Box 25, Item 557)
    Earle Brown Archives EBCD01
  - Brown, Earle: Music for large orchestra and chamber orchestra, 1997, 1 compact disc (Box 25, Item 558)
    Earle Brown Archives EBCD02
  - Foss, Lukas: Echoi, The Fragments of Archilochos, Non-improvisation, 1998, 1 compact disc (Box 25, Item 559)
    Electronic Music Foundation EMF CD 005. Accompanied by manuscript note from Jan Williams.
  - Hoffman, Larry: Works of Larry Hoffman, 2011, 1 compact disc (Box 25, Item 560)
    After Click Publications DBK 701.
  - Leach, Mary Jane: Ariadne's lament +, undated, 1 compact disc (Box 25, Item 561)
    Accompanied by manuscript note from Mary Jane Leach.
  - Reich, Steve: The Cave, 1995, 4 compact discs (Box 25, Item 562)
    Nonesuch 79327-2. Accompanied by note from Nonesuch Records.
  - Reich, Steve: City life, 1996, 1 compact disc (Box 25, Item 563)
    Nonesuch 79430-2. Inscription from Steve Reich to Renée Levine-Packer on jacket sleeve.
  - Reich, Steve: Works, 1965-1995, 1997, 10 compact discs (Box 25, Item 564)
    Nonesuch 79451-2. Inscription from Steve Reich to Renée Levine-Packer on liner notes.
  - Cisneros, J. G.: The Urban-15 group, 1981, 1 audio cassette (Box 25, Item 565)
    Indigenous Musics.
  - Eno, Brian: A space to think: a sound portrait of Brian Eno, undated, 1 audio cassette (Box 25, Item 566)
    Produced by Gail Eichenthal and Lucia DeLisa at 91.5 KUSC FM.
  - Feldman, Morton: Comments before performance of For Philip Guston, 1987, 1 audio cassette (Box 25, Item 567)
    With: Cage, John: Memorial for M. F.
  - Feldman, Morton: Three voices (conclusion), 1983, 1 audio cassette (Box 25, Item 568)
    KUSC FM recording of performance by Joan La Barbara at Cal Arts.
  - La Barbara, Joan: Recent works, 1982-86, 1986, 1 audio cassette (Box 25, Item 569)
  - Mexican music vol. 1, undated, 1 audio cassette (Box 25, Item 570)
  - Tyler, John: Performance today pilot, 1986, 1 audio cassette (Box 25, Item 571)
    National Public Radio
- Book, interview, and research files for Gay Guerrilla: Julius Eastman and His Music, circa 2000-2015, XII.; Folder572-607
  Contains all the files and interview recordings associated with research for the book, Gay Guerrilla: Julius Eastman and His Music.
  Arranged into four subseries:
  A. Research files
  B. Interview and other recordings
  - Research files, circa 2005-2015, XII.A; Folder 572-6,7
    This subseries contains folders related to research for the book, Gay Guerrilla: Julius Eastman and His Music. The contents include subject files, interview transcriptions, and correspondence.
    - Als, Hilton, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 572)
    - Blum, Eberhard, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 573)
    - Brooklyn Philharmonic, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 574)
    - Company of man dance studio Black Ivory production, 1972, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 575)
      Includes score by Roberto Laneri.
    - Curtis Institute of Music, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 576)
    - Degroat, Andrew, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 577)
    - Di Pietro, Rocco, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 578)
    - Eastman, Frances, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 579)
    - Fenley, Molissa, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 580)
    - Gayle, Charles, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 581)
    - Gena, Peter, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 582)
    - Hisama, Ellie, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 583)
    - Hudson, Benjamin, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 584)
    - Ithaca College, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 585)
    - Ithaca High School, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 586)
    - Kahle, Dennis, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 587)
    - Kotík, Petr, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 588)
    - Kubera, Joseph, 1 folder (Box 26, Folder 589)
    - Laneri, Roberto, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 590)
    - Lawson, Christyne, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 591)
    - Leach, Mary Jane, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 592)
    - Lima, Beatriz, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 593)
    - Oliveros, Pauline, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 594)
    - Platt, Russell, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 595)
      Concert announcement in New Yorker.
    - Previte, Bobby, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 596)
    - Putnam, Thomas, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 597)
    - Renart, Marta García, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 598)
    - Russell, Arthur, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 599)
    - Singletary, Karl, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 600)
    - Sokol, Thomas, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 601)
    - State University College at Buffalo. Archives and Special Collections, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 602)
    - State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 603)
      Lists of resources.
    - Stiller, Andrew, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 604)
    - Sublette, Ned, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 605)
    - Suzuki, Zeyda Ruga, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 606)
    - Yates, Peter, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 607)
    - Gay Guerrilla author biographies, 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 608)
  - Interview and other recordings, 1973-2009, XII.B; Item 609-636
    This subseries contains recordings of interviews conducted by Renée Levine Packer about Julius Eastman and some additional recordings.
    Divided by format and then alphabetically arranged by title.
    - Burkhardt, Donald, 2008-11-13, 1 audio cassette (Box 28, Item 609)
    - Eastman, Frances, 2006-10-11, 2009-10-01, 3 audio cassettes (Box 28, Item 610-612)
      Also digitally reformatted on 4 CDs included in container.
    - Eastman, Gerry, 2006-11-02, 1 audio cassette (Box 28, Item 613)
    - Gena, Peter, 2000-05-21, 1 audio cassette (Box 28, Item 614)
    - Levine, George, 2009-12-28, 1 audio cassette (Box 28, Item 615)
    - Sokol, Thomas, 2009-10-01, 1 audio cassette (Box 28, Item 616-617)
    - Dohoney, Ryan, 2008-12-12, 1 microcassette (Box 28, Item 618)
    - Eastman, Gerry, 2009-09-14, 2 microcassettes (Box 28, Item 619-620)
    - Hill, Nemo, 2009-03-06, 2 microcassettes (Box 28, Item 621-622)
    - Hudson, Benjamin, 2007-03-28, 2 microcassettes (Box 28, Item 623-624)
    - Kotík, Petr, 2008-12-11, 2 microcassettes (Box 28, Item 625-626)
      Second tape not labelled, possibly blank.
    - Sublette, Ned, 2008-12-12, 2 microcassettes (Box 28, Item 627-628)
    - Kotík, Petr, 2008-12-11, 1 CD (Box 28, Item 629)
      Inscription on CD envelope: "1st half" - probably a digitally reformatted version of micorcasette recording listed above.
    - Levine Packer, Renée, undated, 1 CD (Box 28, Item 630)
      Interview conducted by Matthew Mendez about Julius Eastman.
    - Hill, Nemo, undated, 1 flash drive (Box 28, Item 631)
      Interview audio files in wav and mp3 format (1 each).
    - Sublette, Ned, undated, 1 flash drive (Box 28, Item 632)
    - Eastman, Julius: Wood In Time; Behrman, David: Players with circuits, 1973-07-06, 1973-07-08, 1 7 inch reel of audio tape (Box 28, Item 633)
    - Eastman, Julius: Wood In Time, 1973-07-06, 1 DVD-R (Box 28, Item 634)
      Contains master preservation file in wav format of above tape.
    - Eastman, Julius: Wood In Time, 1973-07-06, 1 CD (Box 28, Item 635)
      Contains digitally reformatted audio CD format of above tape.
    - Cage, John: Songbooks I, II (excerpt), 1973-12-08, 1 CD (Box 28, Item 636)
      Performance by S.E.M. Ensemble (Jan Williams, Petr Kotík, Julius Eastman, Garret List) at State University of New York at Albany, 8 December 1973.
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Music--20th century; Music--New York (State)--Buffalo--History; Cage, John; Eastman, Julius; Longo, Robert; Reich, Steve, 1936-; State University of New York at Buffalo. Center of the Creative and Performing Arts; State University of New York at Buffalo--History; Levine Packer, Renée, 1940- --Archives
Genres
Correspondence; Interviews; Papers; Photographs; Scores; Sound recordings
Associated Material
Separated Material
The following published books were removed from the collection, either to be added to the general collection, or if duplicates, offered elsewhere.
Writings through John Cage's music, poetry, and art. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 2001.
A Tanglewood dream: the Berkshire Music Center 25th anniversary album, 1940-1965. Lenox, Mass.: Koussevitzky Music Foundation, ©1965.
Source: music of the avant-garde, 1966-1973. Berkeley: University of California Press, ©2011.
Soundings no. 12. Santa Fe, N.M.: Soundings Press, 1981.
Soundings: Neuberger Museum. Purchase, N.Y.: Neuberger Museum, State University of New York, 1981.
The San Francisco Tape Music Center: 1960s counterculture and the avant-garde. Berkeley: University of California Press, ©2008.
Ostrava Days report: New Music Institute and festival. Ostrava, Czech Republic: Ostrava Center for New Music, ©2002-
Opera annual. Garden City: Doubleday and Co., ©1958.
The Monthly musical record. London: Augener, 1871-1887
Lecture on the weather: John Cage in Buffalo. Buffalo, NY: Burchfield-Penney Art Center, Buffalo State College, ©2010.
A John Cage reader: in celebration of his 70th birthday. [Evanston, Ill.]: [Northwestern University], [1982]
Da Capo best music writing 2004: the year's finest writing on rock, hip-hop, jazz, pop, country, and more. Cambridge, Mass.: Da Capo, 2004.
Concert music, rock, and jazz since 1945: essays and analytical studies. Rochester, NY: University of Rochester Press, 2002, ©1995.
Carlos Chávez 1899-1978: iconografía. [México, D.F.]: Consejo Nacional para la Cultura y las Artes, Instituto Nacional de Bellas Artes, ©1994.
American mavericks San Francisco, Calif.: San Francisco Symphony; ©2001.
Wish you were here: the Buffalo avant-garde in the 1970s. Buffalo, N.Y.: Albright-Knox Art Gallery, ©2012.
Annual report, 1964-1965, 1972-1973. [Buffalo, N.Y.] Buffalo Fine Arts Academy: 1965, 1973
Artpark, the program in the visual arts / Sharon Edelman. Lewiston, N.Y.: Artpark, ©1976.
IRCAM, Centre Georges Pompidou, EIC, Ensemble Inter-Contemporain, director: Pierre Boulez: US tour, 1986: a commemorative program book. [Paris]: IRCAM éditions, 1986.
SECA presents Firing line: subject, "a musical question: to perform or not perform". Columbia, S.C.: Southern Educational Communications Association, ©1986.
Bannon, Anthony The Photo-Pictorialists of Buffalo.
Barzun, Jacques Berlioz and the romantic century. Boston, Little, Brown, 1950.
Beal, Amy C. New music, new allies: American experimental music in West Germany from the zero hour to reunification. Berkeley: University of California Press, ©2006.
Berg, Alban Lulu: opera in 3 acts (7 scenes). [Wien]: Universal Edition, ©1978.
Bie, Oskar Die oper. Berlin, S. Fischer, 1923.
Bizet, Georges Carmen Prague: Statni opera praha, [2004?]
Blum, Eberhard Visual work 1980-1998. Berlin: [publisher not identified], 1998.
Blum, Eberhard Choice and chance: Bilder und Berichte aus meinem Leben als Musiker. Berlin: Berlinische Gallerie, ©2008.
Born, Georgina. Rationalizing culture: IRCAM, Boulez, and the institutionalization of the musical avant-garde. Berkeley: University of California Press, ©1995.
Brown, Richard Carl Buffalo, lake city in Niagara land: an illustrated history. [Woodland Hills, Calif.]: Windsor Publications, 1981.
Cage, John Notations. [New York], [Something Else Press], [1969]
Cage, John. A year from Monday; new lectures and writings. Middletown, Conn., Wesleyan University Press [1967]
Cage, John. Silence: lectures and writings. Middletown, Conn.: Wesleyan University Press, 1961.
Cage, John. John Cage: New River watercolors. Washington, D.C.: Phillips Collection, 1990.
Cale, John. What's Welsh for Zen: the autobiography of John Cale. New York: Bloomsbury, 2000.
Carl, Robert Terry Riley's In C. Oxford; Oxford University Press, 2009.
Cassel Oliver, Valerie. Benjamin Patterson: born in the state of FLUX/us. Houston, Tex.: Contemporary Arts Museum Houston, ©2012.
Copland, Aaron What to listen for in music. New York: Mentor, 1999.
Copland, Aaron Music and imagination. New York: New American Library, 1959, ©1952.
Cornish, Nellie Centennial Miss Aunt Nellie; the autobiography of Nellie C. Cornish. Seattle, University of Washington Press [1964]
Crawford, Dorothy L. Evenings on and off the roof: pioneering concerts in Los Angeles, 1939-1971. Berkeley: University of California, Press, ©1995.
Crow, Thomas E. The rise of the sixties: American and European art in the era of dissent. New Haven, CT: Yale University Press, ©1996
Darrell, R. D. Good listening; with a rev. and up-to-date index-discography. [New York]: New American Library, [1955]
Davis, W. Bowdoin. Duchamp: domestic patterns, covers and threads. New York: Midmarch Arts Press, 2002.
Di Pietro, Rocco Dialogues with Boulez. Lanham, Md.: Scarecrow Press, 2001.
Dufallo, Richard Trackings: composers speak with Richard Dufallo. New York: Oxford University Press, 1989.
Echols, Alice. Hot stuff: disco and the remaking of American culture. New York: W.W. Norton and Co., 2011.
Eisenberg, Evan The recording angel: explorations in phonography. New York: McGraw-Hill, ©1987.
Feldman, Morton Morton Feldman says: selected interviews and lectures 1964-1987. London: Hyphen Press, 2006.
Feldman, Morton Give my regards to Eighth Street: collected writings of Morton Feldman. Cambridge, MA: Exact Change, ©2000.